A racing second hand, a glittering shooting star!
عقرب دقائق مسرِع، مُذنّب لامع
Conan's logic is good medicine for hearts dried by modern society!
استنتاجات كونان دواء ممتاز للقلوب !التي جفّفها المجتمع الحديث
Today's case is a sad memory hidden behind bandages!
قضيّة اليوم تتضمّن ذكرى حزينة تختبئ خلف الضمادات
He sees the single truth for what it is,
يرى الحقيقة الواحدة
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
يحمل مظهر طفل، لكنّ عقله عقل بالغ
His name? Detective Conan!
!اسمه المتحرّي كونان
During the birthday party of the Nagato Group president,
،أثناء حفلة عيد ميلاد رئيس مجموعة ناغاتو
Mitsuaki-san, husband of 2nd daughter Yasue-san,
،تعرّض ميتسواكي-سان، زوج الابنة الثانية ياسوي-سان
was attacked by someone in the room below!
لهجوم من قِبل أحدهم في الغرفة السفلية
The eldest son, Hideomi-san, appeared on the veranda
ظهر الابن الأكبر، هيدومي-سان، على الشرفة
with a knife in his mouth!
!بسكّينٍ في فمه
We rushed to the room below but were too late...
أسرعنا للغرفة السفليّة لكن الأوان كان قد فات
Mitsuaki-san had been impaled on the fence below!
اخترق ميتسواكي الأسوار الحديدية ولقي حتفه
Two days later, Hideomi-san's body was found in the pond,
بعد يومين للحادثة، وجدنا جثّة هيدومي-سان في البركة
along with his will!
مع وصيّة له
It seemed certain that he had done it...
وبدا أنّه مُرتكب الجريمة بلا شكّ
There's something unnatural about that will!
هناك شيءٌ غريب حيال تلك الوصية
In other words, Hideomi-san had been murdered before it happened!
مما يعني أنّ هيدومي-سان !قُتل قبل وقوع الجريمة
"The Case of the Eminent Family's Strange Deaths (Part 2)."
قضيّة سلسلة حوادث الموت الغريبة للعائلة المرموقة ا(لجزء الثاني)
What?! Nobody left?!
ماذا؟ لم يغادر أحد؟
None of them left the premises.
لم يغادر أحد بينهم المحيط
They went inside before evening...
دخلوا القصر جميعاً قبل المساء
Your father told us to be especially alert, too...
أخبرنا والدك أن نتوخّى الحذر تحديداً ذاك اليوم
There's no mistake.
لا شكّ في الأمر
After all, we only left the front door for one or two minutes
فقد تركنا المدخل لمجرّد دقيقة أو اثنتين
when we discovered the body with you.
عندما ذهبنا لمكان الجثّة معك
Hideomi-san must've used that chance to enter the pond
لا بدّ أنّ هيدومي-سان استغلّ تلك الفرصة لدخول البركة
from the other direction.
من الاتّجاه الآخر
The late Mitsuaki-san was the only one who went outside.
كان ميتسواكي-سان هو الوحيد الذي خرج
Mitsuaki-san did?! When was this?!
ميتسواكي-سان؟ متى فعل ذلك؟
I'd say about 9:30...
...عند التاسعة والنصف تقريباً
He said he was looking for Hideomi-san...
قال أنّه يبحث عن هيدومي-سان
He was searching all over. Between trees, around the pond...
...كان يبحث في كلّ مكان، بين الأشجار وحول البركة
Anything strange about Hideomi-san lately?
شيء غريب في هيدومي-سان مؤخراً؟
Yeah! Anything at all! Like, was anything bothering him?
!نعم، أيّ شيء يفي بالغرض أكان هناك ما يشغله؟
Not sure. He didn't talk much.
لا أدري، لم يكن كثير الكلام
Oh, yeah! His meals!
!صحيح، وجباته
His meals?
وجباته؟
He ate much more than usual the day of the murder and the day before!
أكل أكثر بكثير من العادة يوم الحادثة وفي اليوم السابق لها
Yeah! He even ate dessert for once!
!صحيح! أكل التحلية التي يتركها دائماً حتّى
It was surprising because he rarely even ate breakfast!
كان ذلك مُفاجئاً بما أنّه لا يتناول الإفطار عادةً
Say, did Hideomi-san always wear the same bandages?
هل كان هيدومي-سان يرتدي نفس الضمادات باستمرار؟
No, Yasue-san changed them every three days.
كلا، كانت شقيقته ياسوي-سان تغيّرها كل ثلاثة أيام
I think they were last changed two days before the incident...
أظنّ آخر مرة كانت قبل يومين من الحادثة
Wait, there was something weird!
!تذكّرت، كان هناك أمر غريب
One of his sheets disappeared three days ago!
!اختفت إحدى أغطية فراشه قبل ثلاثة أيام
Did you count right?!
هل عددتِ كما يجب؟
Yeah...
أجل
Hey, Kudo! Come with me!
كودو! تعال معي قليلاً
Over here!
!هنا
Check it out.
انظر لذلك
The bottom of Mitsuaki-san's and Yasue-san's veranda.
أسفل شرفة غرفة ميتسواكي-سان وياسوي-سان
What's that mark? It's like something hit it...
...ما ذاك الأثر؟ يبدو أنّه ارتطام شيء
And that's the veranda Mitsuaki-san was pushed off of...
كانت هذه الشرفة التي دُفع منها ميتسواكي-سان وفقما أظن
Hey!
!تعال
There's some here, too!
!يوجد الأثر نفسه هنا
But, there's a lot more on this one.
رغم أنّها آثار كثيرة، وليست واحداً
Whose room is that?
هذه غرفة من؟
Nobuko-san's.
نوبوكو-سان
Seems mighty fishy...
...يبدو مُريباً
Alright! Let's check it out!
!حسناً، لنذهب لتفقد الأمر
You sure about this, Kudo?!
أأنت واثق من هذا يا كودو؟
This makes us no different than thieves!
!لا فرق بيننا واللصوص
It's fine!
!لا مشكلة
No, it's not fine...
لا مشكلة؟
It's the phone! What do we do?!
!الـ-الهاتف! ماذا نفعل؟
This is Nobuko.
نعم، معك نوبوكو
He's got some guts...
...يا لجرأته
So, what is it you want?
إذاً، ماذا تريد؟
Remember those drunken messages you left me two days ago?
أتذكرين الرسالة التي تركتِها على آلة الرد خاصتي أثناء ثملك قبل يومين؟
What time two days ago?
متى قبل يومين بالضبط؟
You mean you forgot?
أنسيتِ؟
You left a bunch of half-hour messages before 10:00 at night...
تركتِ مجموعةً من الرسائل بطول نصف ساعة قبل العاشرة ليلاً
Oh, I did?
ماذا؟ أحقّاً ذلك؟
You don't remember, so never mind. Bye!
لا يهمّ إذا كنتِ لا تذكرين، إلى اللقاء
10:00 pm two nights ago was when the murder happened!
العاشرة مساءً قبل يومين أي عندما وقعت الجريمة
Yeah.
نعم
That at least means the bandaged man on the veranda
عرفنا أنّ رجل الضماد الذي أرانا وجهه على الشرفة
wasn't Nobuko-san.
لم يكن نوبوكو-سان على الأقل
That means only Hideomi-san coulda done it!
ما يعني أنّ الوحيد القادر على ذلك !هو هيدومي-سان فقط
Let's look around his room for now!
!بأيّ حال، لنبحث في غرفته
All these books! He was a writer, all right!
!إنّها تعجّ بالكتب! كما تتوقّع من روائيّ
Just look who's trashing the place up...
...أنتَ من يعبث الآن
An answering machine!
!آلة رد
We got some messages here!
وردت فيها رسائل على ما يبدو
Really?!
!حقّاً؟
Let's listen!
لنسمعها
Hi! This is Yamada from Literature Era!
"مرحباً، أنا يامادا من "عصر الأدب
I'll be at the usual place at 1:00 tomorrow
سأكون في المكان المعتاد عند الواحدة بعد الظهر غداً
to discuss your next manuscript!
!لمناقشة نصّك التالي
October 31st, 1:28 pm.
الواحد والثلاثون من أكتوبر، 1:28 مساءً
October 31st? That's the day before the incident...
الواحد والثلاثون من أكتوبر؟ أي اليوم السابق للجريمة
This is Yamada. I'm at the usual coffee shop.
أنا يامادا، وصلتُ المقهى المعتاد
November 1st, 3:04 pm.
الأوّل من نوفمبر، 3:04 مساءً
This is Yamada. I waited for six hours.
أنا يامادا، انتظرتُ 6 ساعات
I guess you can't come, so I'll be going.
يبدو أنّك لن تأتي لذا سأغادر
Hey! Don't tell me Hideomi-san was actually--
...أيمكن أنّ هيدومي-سان
Yeah, right! His estimated time of death was...
...مستحيل! وقت وفاته المقدّر
There was a way after all!
!كانت هناك طريقة إذاً
Yeah! And only that person could've done it!
نعم، وذاك الشخص وحده !من كان يستطيع فعلها
Which means...
...ما يعني
...it should be here!
غرفة ميتسواكي وياسوي
If our theory is correct, it's probably in here...
...إذا أصاب استنتاجنا
Bingo!
!وجدتُه
A muddy sheet! Oh, and a swimming cap!
!غطاء فراش متّسخ بالوحل
Found what I was looking for, too!
وجدتُ ما أبحث عنه بدوري
Here you are, Hattori-kun!
ها أنت يا هاتّوري-كن
Give Miyuki-san her pen back now!
!أعد قلم ميوكي-سان لها
Sorry! I forgot!
!آسف، آسف! نسيت
We're leaving now, Conan-kun. It's already dark out...
هيّا، سنرجع يا كونان-كن فالظلام قد خيّم
What time is it?
كم الساعة الآن؟
10 to 7:00...
السابعة إلّا عشر دقائق
Great! The store's still open!
!حسناً، لا يزال المتجر مفتوحاً
Ran-neechan! Could you buy these for us?
ران-نيتشان، هلّا اشتريتِ هذه لنا من فضلك؟
Oh, and do you know who used the room above Nobuko-san's?
وأيضاً، أتعرفان من كان يقطن الغرفة فوق غرفة نوبوكو-سان؟
I am for now...
...إنّها أنا حالياً
Then, please have everyone come there in one hour!
فلتطلبي من الجميع القدوم هناك خلال ساعة من فضلك
I'll watch this runt until then!
!سأبقي هذا الصبيّ معي حتّى حينها
Wait!
!لحظة
Tell old man Kogoro to come right away!
!أخبري العمّ كوغورو أن يأتي فوراً
What's with them?!
!ما خطبهما؟
We put the old man to sleep with the tranquilizer gun...
نوّمنا الرجل المُسن بالساعة المخدّرة
We had them buy everything we need for our theory...
حصلنا على كلّ ما نحتاجه لعرض استنتاجنا
And our logic is flawless!
!والاستنتاج لا تشوبه شائبة
But, we forgot something important...
لكن، نسينا أمراً مهماً
Yeah.
نعم
The proof. We have no proof!
!الدليل، لا دليل لدينا
We were so focused on our theory that we completely forgot...
كنا منهمكين في الاستنتاج وغفلنا عن ذلك تماماً
Hey. What time is it?
ما الساعة الآن؟
7:40. They'll be here in ten minutes.
السابعة وأربعون دقيقة، سيأتي الجميع بعد عشر دقائق
Why didn't you realize it!
!لمَ لم تدرك الأمر؟
Aren't you the great eastern detective!
ألستَ متحرّي الشرق العظيم؟
Shut up! You're the western...
...أيّها الأحمق! ألستَ متحرّي الغرب
Wait!
لحظة
Why did that person...
...لمَ ذاك الشخص
Now I see!
فهمت
So that was it!
!هكذا إذاً
OK! We'll begin in ten minutes, as scheduled!
حسناً، سنبدأ بعد عشر دقائق وفق الجدول
What's wrong?
ما الخطب؟
Say, Hattori.
أخبرني يا هاتّوري
Have you ever killed someone?
أسبق وقتلتَ أحدهم؟
We're here, Hattori-kun. What's this about?
أتينا يا هاتّوري-كن، ما الأمر بالضبط؟
Huh? Where's Hattori-kun?
ماذا؟ أين هاتّوري-كن؟
It was I who called you here.
أنا من استدعاكم جميعاً
You did?
أنت يا أبي؟
What's going on?
ما الذي يجري؟
I finally figured out who killed Mitsuaki-san
اكتشفتُ أخيراً هويّة المجرم الذي قتل ميتسواكي-سان
and threw Hideomi-san into the pond!
وألقى هيدومي-سان في البركة
Hey, now. It was Hideomi-san who killed Mitsuaki-san!
مهلك، كان هيدومي-سان !من قتل ميتسواكي-سان
Then he poisoned himself in the pond!
ثمّ سمّم نفسه وانتحر في البركة
Even the handwriting on the will matched up with--
حتّى خطّ الوصيّة موافق ...لخطّ هيدومي-سان تماماً
The phone...
...الـ-الهاتف
Now, then, Inspector. Please pick it up.
إذاً يا حضرة المفتّش، هلا أجبت؟
Do so and the tragic night Mitsuaki-san died on the fence
...افعل ذلك وسيتكرر أمامنا مشهد
Hello?
مرحباً؟
Heya! It's me!
!إنّه أنا
Oh, it's just you...
...ماذا؟ أنت يا هاتّوري-كن
What the hell're you doing?!
!ما الذي تفعله يا هذا؟
Hey! What's going on?!
!ما الخطب؟
Someone cut the lights and attacked--
...أطفأ أحدهم الأنوار وهاجمني
Where are you?!
أين أنت الآن؟
The room below! Take a look!
!في الغرفة أسفلكم! ألق نظرة
What the...
!ماذا؟
What is going on?!
ما الذي يجري؟
I don't know! But we have to save him!
!لا أدري، لكن علينا النزول وإنقاذه فوراً
Stop right there.
تمهل رجاءً
This was how the killer drove everyone from the room...
هكذا أخرج القاتل الجميع من الغرفة آنذاك
to hide the terrifying truth that happened in here afterward.
لإخفاء الحقيقة المرعبة التي حصلت هنا بعدها
W-Who are you?!
!مـ-من أنت؟
It's me.
إنّه أنا
Hattori-kun?!
!هاتّوري-كن؟
The alarming phone call and the knife and bandaged face
الاتّصال المُفزع والسكّين بالفمّ ...والوجه الملفوف بالضماد
were all an act by Mitsuaki-san to frame Hideomi-san!
كانت كلها تمثيلاً من ميتسواكي-سان لإلفاق التهمة بهيدومي-سان
That's absurd! The killer was covered in Mitsuaki-san's blood!
لا-لا يمكن! كان القاتل يحمل !دماء ميتسواكي-سان
And there were cuts on Mitsuaki-san's body!
كما كانت هناك آثار جروح سكّين على جثّة ميتسواكي-سان
Those cuts he made himself.
كانت تلك الآثار من صنعه
The blood was applied to the bandaged face with a syringe.
رشّ الدم على ضمادات الوجه بمحقنة طبيّة
The bandages and hat likely belonged to Hideomi-san.
كانت الضمادات والقبعة تخصّ هيدومي-سان غالباً
So he wore a swimming cap to keep his own hairs out.
لذا ارتدى قبعة سباحة كيلا يلتصق شعره
We found the syringe and cap in Mitsuaki-san's room!
وجدنا المحقنة وقبّعة السباحة في غرفة ميتسواكي-سان
But, Mitsuaki-san was the one murdered! Why would he do all that?
!لكن، كان ميتسواكي من قُتِل لمَ قد يفعل كلّ هذا؟
Most likely to murder President Nagato.
لقتل الرئيس ناغاتو على الأرجح
The president?!
الرئيس؟
Yes. The same president his accomplice drugged.
نعم، الرئيس الذي خدّره شريكه ونوّمه
Accomplice?!
!شريكه؟
That's right.
صحيح
The plan was probably for Mitsuaki-san to kill the president
كانت الخطّة هي قتل ميتسواكي-سان ...للرئيس غالباً
and return below while his accomplice kept everyone downstairs.
ويرجع لغرفته بينما يُبقي شريكه الجميع في الأسفل
But, he was killed by his accomplice instead.
لكنّه قُتل على يد شريكه بدل ذلك
Killed by the person who stayed behind...
يد ذاك الشخص الذي ...بقي مع الرئيس في الغرفة
...you, Hyuga Miyuki-san!
!هيوغا ميوكي-سان، أنت
Mitsuaki-san musta been shocked
لا بدّ أنّ ميتسواكي-سان كان مصدوماً
to see you on the veranda of the supposedly-empty room.
عندما رآك في شرفة الغرفة التي يُفترض أنّها تحوي الرئيس فقط
So much so that he fell off!
وفوق ذلك، قمتِ بدفعه
But, then he should've fallen with the knife on him!
لكن يُفترض أنّ السكّين سقطت معه في تلك الحالة
He likely tossed his knife, bandages, and hat outside before his climb.
رمى السكّين والضمادات والقبّعة خارجاً قبل صعوده على الأرجح
Mitsuaki-san planned to strangle the president with the grappling hook
نوى ميتسواكي-سان قتل الرئيس بخيط رفيع
in his jacket pocket!
في جيب معطفه
Naturally, Miyuki-san's only target was Mitsuaki-san.
هدف ميوكي-سان الوحيد كان ميتسواكي-سان بالطبع
Nobody would suspect a dead man had used a trick!
لن يشكّ أحد أنّ رجلاً مقتولاً استعمل حيلة
Then what was that grappling hook?
ماذا عن الحبل بالخطّاف إذاً؟
That's simple.
ذلك بسيط
She pulled his rope in, grabbed the weight on the opposite end,
سحبت الحبل الذي استعمله ميتسواكي-سان وأمسكت بالثقل في طرفه الآخر
then lowered it onto the railing below.
ثمّ علّقته بأسوار الشرفة السفلية
When she tossed the other end over...
...بعدها، ألقت نهاية الطرف الثاني
the weight hit the bottom of the veranda and it stopped on its own!
فأصاب الثقل الجانب السفليّ للشرفة وتوقّف من تلقاء نفسه
As proof, there are marks on the bottom of the verandas
ودليلاً على ذلك، توجد آثار اصطدام ثقل
in the president's room and Mitsuaki-san's room.
في أسفل شرفة غرفة الرئيس، كما شرفة غرفة ميتسواكي-سان
And, on Nobuko-san's veranda below us.
وأيضاً شرفة غرفة نوبوكو-سان أسفلنا
Miyuki-san probably tested it the day before to see if it was possible.
اختبرت ميوكي-سان فعالية الأمر في اليوم السابق للحادثة غالباً
The day before?
اليوم السابق؟
Yes. The president had heard it.
نعم، لقد سمع الرئيس الصوت
He did...
الرئيس؟
Yes. And the sound of someone running through the hall.
أجل، مع صوت ركض أحدهم في الرواق
Those footsteps belonged to Miyuki-san, who was calculating the time
كانت تلك خطوات ميوكي-سان التي كانت تحسب الوقت الذي ستستغرقه
to run from Mitsuaki-san's room to the spare key and back.
للركض من غرفة ميتسواكي-سان إلى المخزن لجلب المفتاح الاحتياطيّ ثمّ العودة
In other words, she had planned this murder the day before!
أي أنّها كانت جريمة قتل جهّزت لها ميوكي-سان في اليوم السابق
Are you saying she killed Hideomi-san, too? And what about the will?!
أتقصد أنّها قتلت هيدومي-سان أيضاً؟ وماذا عن الوصيّة؟
I already told you, Inspector. Her only target was Mitsuaki-san.
أخبرتُك حضرة المفتّش، هدفها الوحيد كان ميتسواكي-سان
What?!
!ماذا؟
The will was written by Hideomi-san,
الوصيّة كتبها هيدومي-سان
who committed suicide the day before.
في اليوم السابق قبل إقدامه على الانتحار
The day before?!
!اليوم السابق؟
Yes.
أجل
Miyuki-san most likely found him dead in his room
وجدته ميوكي-سان في غرفته بعد انتحاره غالباً
and then devised this murder!
ثمّ خطّطت لهذه الجريمة
But, Mori-kun. The coroner calculated his time of death--
لكن يا موري-كن، قدّر الطبيب الشرعيّ ...وقت وفاة هيدومي-سان، ولم يكن
The ground.
كان مدفوناً في الأرض
Eh?
ماذا؟
If you put a body in the ground and deprive it of air,
إذا دفنت الجثّة في الأرض وحبست الهواء عنها
it will decay at 1/8 the normal rate.
سيتقلّص معدل تعفّنها بمقدار الثُمن
She probably had Mitsuaki-san help her wrap him in a sheet,
استدعت ميوكي-سان ميتسواكي-سان غالباً ولفّا هيدومي-سان بغطاء فراش
and then they secretly buried him by the pond in the morning!
ثمّ دفناه سرّاً في الصباح قُرب البركة
There were already lots of holes for trees to be planted in,
كانت توجد الكثير من الحفر سلفاً لتُزرع بها أشجار
so nobody would notice an extra one.
فلن يلاحظ أحد زيادة حفرة إضافية
So, who threw him in the pond?
من أغرقه في البركة إذاً؟
Mitsuaki-san.
ميتسواكي-سان
He dug him up and threw him in there just before the murder...
أخرجه قبل وقوع الجريمة ورماه في البركة
While pretending to look for him, of course...
بينما كان يتظاهر بالبحث عنه بالطبع
But, we saw Hideomi-sama the day of the murder...
...لكنّنا رأينا هيدومي-ساما يوم الجريمة
Nope. What you saw was a disguised Miyuki-san or Mitsuaki-san.
كلا، ما رأيتموه هي ميوكي-سان أو ميتسواكي-سان متنكّران على هيئته
It was clear once we checked his answering machine
تبيّن لنا بوضوح بعدما استمعنا ...للرسائل على آلة الردّ خاصته
that he was dead the day before the murder!
أنّه كان ميتاً في اليوم السابق للجريمة
But, why did Mitsuaki-san go along with Miyuki-san's plan?
لكن، لمَ تعاون ميتسواكي-سان مع ميوكي-سان في خطّتها؟
She probably told him this,
:أخبرتُه بشيء على هذا السياق غالباً
"I have a good way for you to take the title of president
لديّ طريقة ممتازة لتأخذ منصب الرئيس"
and place all the blame on Hideomi-san."
"وتلقي كلّ اللوم على هيدومي-سان
That can't be! He saved her life! She couldn't possibly frame him!
!لا يمكن
Besides, you don't even have proof!
!لا تقل كلاماً كهذا بلا دليل
Do you have the time, Miyuki-san?
ما الساعة الآن يا ميوكي-سان؟
What's that have to do with anything, Dad?
لحظة، ما الذي تتكلّم عنه يا أبي؟
Oh? What happened to your watch?
عجباً، ماذا حلّ بساعة معصمك؟
Um, I just forgot to--
...إنّها... صادف أن نسيتُ اليوم
No, you didn't forget to put it on. You can't put it on.
كلا، لم تنسيها، بل لم تستطيعي ارتداءها
Because its strap broke.
فقد انكسر رباطها آنذاك
When you pushed Mitsuaki-san off the veranda,
،عندما دفعتِ ميتسواكي-سان من الشرفة
he caught on to your watch strap.
تمسّك برباط ساعتك
If he tore it off, your watch would land with his body.
إذا نزعها، ستكون ساعتك بجوار موضع سقوطه
Flustered, you used something on you to stab his right hand!
في هلعك، استعملتِ شيئاً كان معك !وطعنتِ يد ميتسواكي-سان اليُمنى
Something? Don't tell me it was...
...شيئاً كان معها؟ أ-أيمكن
her pen?!
!قلم الحبر؟
Yes. She removed the cap with her mouth and stabbed him
نعم، نزعت الغطاء بفمها وطعنته
with her father's keepsake pen!
بالقلم التذكار من أبيها
But, how did you find that out?
لكن كيف عرفتم ذلك؟
I took the cap off to write some notes and saw the tip was bent!
خلعتُ الغطاء لكتابة بعض الملاحظات ووجدتُ رأس القلم ملتوياً
Not even a fire could bend something like that!
لا يمكن حتّى لنار الحريق التي خرج منها القلم أن تثنيه هكذا
But, why would Miyuki-san do that?!
لكن لمَ قد تفعل ميوكي-سان هذا؟
The fire was probably the cause.
كان الحريق الدافع غالباً
If our theory is correct, the ones who started that fire twenty years ago...
...إذا أصاب استنتاجنا، فمن أضرم الحريق قبل 20 عاماً
...were Hideomi-san and Mitsuaki-san!
!كانا هيدومي-سان وميتسواكي-سان
What?!
!ما-ماذا؟
Assuming Hideomi-san didn't fix his burn scars to atone for his sin...
بافتراض أنّ هيدومي-سان لم يُعالج ...آثار الحروق على وجهه للتكفير عن ذنبه
And if there was more to his will in which he confessed everything...
...وأنّ هناك تتمة لوصيّته اعترف فيها بكلّ شيء
...everything would fit.
ستكتمل الصورة
Now I see. It was revenge for her parents who died in the fire...
فهمت، كان انتقاماً لوالديها اللذين ماتا في الحريق إذاً
But, one thing doesn't make sense.
لكن هناك شيءٌ لا أفهمه
Why did you make Nobuko-san angry so we'd find Hideomi-san?
لمَ استفززتِ نوبوكو-سان وقدتِنا لإيجاد هيدومي-سان؟
You did that on purpose, right?
فعلتِ ذلك عمداً، أليس كذلك؟
The police would've found him soon enough...
كانت الشرطة لتعثر عليه قريباً لو تركتِه وحسب
I didn't want to leave him in that cold water any more...
لم أرد تركه في الماء البارد أكثر
Miyuki-san!
!ميوكي-سان
Stay away! There's gasoline inside here!
!لا تقتربوا! يوجد بنزين في هذا الوعاء
Hey, now! Don't do anything foolish--
...مهلك! لا تُقدمي على أيّ حماقات
I'm serious!
!أنا جادة
Miyuki-san...
...ميوكي-سان
The detective's right! His will explained everything about the fire!
ما قاله ذاك المتحرّي صحيح، كان كلّ شيء عن الحريق مكتوباً في وصيّته
They had to pay... The carefree Mitsuaki...
...لم أستطع مسامحتهما
and Hideomi-san, who never said a word about it...
وهيدومي-سان الذي أخفى الأمر طوال الوقت
But, I...
...لكن، أنا
...couldn't help but fall in love with him!
!وقعتُ في حبّه، بلا حيلة لي
He risked his life to save me!
!خاطر بحياته لإنقاذي
He always came to cheer me up after I lost my family!
كان يأتي دوماً لزيارتي وإبهاجي !بعدما فقدتُ عائلتي
And he accepted my proposal!
كما قبِل عرضي للزواج
But Hideomi-san is gone now...
...لكنّ هيدومي-سان رحل الآن
I'm all alone again... I have to hurry to him...
...أصبحتُ وحدي مجدداً
No!
!كلا
That's pointless.
لا جدوى
There's only water inside.
لا يوجد سوى ماء في الوعاء
Why? Why?!
!لمَ؟ لمَ؟
Why?! Why?! Why?!
!لمَ؟! لمَ؟! لمَ؟
His fire lit so easily! Why won't mine?!
!أضرم ناره بسهولة، فلمَ لا أستطيع إضرام ناري؟
Y'know, Kudo. Maybe we shoulda let her die after all...
اسمع يا كودو، ربما كان علينا تركها تموت
Don't be dumb.
أيّها الأحمق
A detective who corners someone with logic,
المتحرّي الذي يحاصر المجرم باستنتاجاته
but lets them commit suicide, is no different from a murderer.
ويجرّه للانتحار لا يختلف عن القاتل
There's no such thing as a perfect person.
لا يوجد شخص مثاليّ في هذا العالم
Even I'm just one person...
...حتّى أنا لم أستطع إنقاذ مجرّد شخص
Just one person...
...مجرّد شخص
Besides, I'm sure "he'll" save Miyuki-san.
كما أنا متأكد أنّ "ذاك الشخص" سينقذ ميوكي-سان
"He"?
ذاك الشخص؟
That's enough, Hyuga-kun.
يكفي يا هيوغا-كن
No more foolish talk about following Hideomi...
اتركي الكلام السخيف عن اللحاق بهيدومي
Sir!
!سيّدي
Your mother wasn't that sort of person.
لم تكن أمّك من هذا الصنف
What would you know?! You never knew her!
!وما أدراك؟! لم تعرف أمّي قطّ
But I did!
بلى
After all, that pen of yours is a present I gave your mother
...فقلم الحبر الذي معك هو هديّة منّي
when she transferred to my grade school!
لأمّك عندما انتقلت لمدرستي الابتدائية
It seems you thought it was your father's, though.
يبدو أنّكِ ظننتِ أنّه لوالدك
I won't ask you to forgive what Hideomi did,
لن أطلب منك مسامحة هيدومي على فعلته
but you're still young! Your life's just begun!
لكنّكِ لا تزالين شابة، حياتك في مُقتبلها
Live strongly for Hideomi, too!
احرصي على العيش لأجل هيدومي أيضاً
I'm certain your mother wishes that as well!
فأنا متأكد أنّها رغبة أمّك كذلك
Shin-Yokohama Station
محطّة شين يوكوهاما
What?!
!ماذا؟
His first love was Miyuki-san's mother?!
!محبوبة الرئيس الأولى كانت أمّ ميوكي-سان؟
Yeah, probably. So he made up that lie to cover for her.
نعم، غالباً. لذا اختلق تلك الكذبة للتستر على ميوكي-سان
I thought he lied and said, "Miyuki-san was with me the whole time,"
فهمت، ظننتُ ادّعاءه أنّ ميوكي-سان ...كانت بجواره طوال الوقت
as atonement for his son, but I guess it had another meaning!
كان للتكفير عن ذنب ابنه، لكن كان هناك سبب آخر
I bet he wanted to see his first love
شعر برغبة في رؤية محبوبته الأولى
because he saw her image in Miyuki-san's face!
عندما رآها في ملامح ميوكي-سان بالتأكيد
Alright, Kudo. Don't tell me you knew that the whole time!
أنت، لا تخبرني يا كودو أنّك أدركت ذلك وأخفيته عني؟
You said "Kudo" again!
!قلتَ كودو مجدداً
Don't tell me "Kudo" means--
...أتقصد بكودو
No, I said, "Kudoi (annoying)!"
...لا، ما قلتُه
This runt wanted details about the incident, more
أصرّ هذا القزم على سماع المزيد عن القضيّة
so I called him annoying!
!فقلتُ يا لإلحاحك فقط
You're from Osaka, all right!
كما تتوقّع من ابن أوساكا
I'm the Japanese king of comedy!
!الأفضل في اليابان في التلاعب
So, when the killer struck at Maejima-san with the wooden sword,
عندما همّ الفاعل بضرب مايجيما-سان ...بسيف خشبيّ
this cell phone in Maejima-san's pocket rang?
رنّ هذا الهاتف الخلويّ الذي كان في جيب مايجيما-سان إذاً؟
No! There's another side to this case!
!كلا، يوجد جانب خلفيّ لهذه القضيّة
On the next Conan... "The Bank Robbery Murder Case."
في الحلقة القادمة من كونان
Next Conan Hint:
تلميح الحلقة القادمة
Cellphone
هاتف خلوي
Next episode's case is interesting.
!قضيّة الحلقة القادمة مسليّة
Won't answer my calls? "Cell" that phone. Lame!
...هاتفه الخلويّ